<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-01T00:44:58+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">amateur math blog</title><subtitle>This is my personal blog. I&apos;m unsure about what this will contain. For now I&apos;ll post about my intersts here. Since that mostly consists of math and coding (making this website), that is what you&apos;ll find here!
</subtitle><author><name>Your Name</name></author><entry><title type="html">Making this blog - P2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/29/making-this-blog-p2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making this blog - P2" /><published>2023-06-29T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-06-29T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/29/making-this-blog-p2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/29/making-this-blog-p2.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="katex-vs-mathjax">Katex vs MathJax</h1>

<p>So today I tried to implement Katex. Its an alternative to MathJax with the advantage that it doesn’t take a stupidly long time to render and does not spill its gooey latex insides around while rendering. But Katex seems to have two problems</p>

<ol>
  <li>Some of its font doesn’t match that of MathJax or Latex at all. Even in math mode all the characters feel like they have been written inside <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">\text{}</code>. It looks ugly and isn’t ideal but I was ready to reach a compromise somehow but that wouldn’t be possible because,</li>
  <li>Github, for some reason, doesn’t exactly like Katex. I dont understand the technicality of how or why, but it just feels too complicated to add Katex support right now. I mean it is very tempting but then it also isn’t an immediate necessity for the blog. It can wait.</li>
</ol>

<p>So in this round of <em>Katex vs MathJax</em>, MathJax wins. I’ll come around to this problem later in the future.</p>

<h1 id="whats-next">What’s Next</h1>

<p>The terrible feeling that I’ll have to finally dip my toe into actual Web Dev, and understand properly what I’m doing, just keeps growing day by day. Customising the blog on my own will require proper css and html knowledge that I don’t posess right now. And while it’ll be intersting to learn, I don’t think I can learn at a pace where I can also implement what I’m learning at the same time. I say its a terrible feeling because its a far longer process than just installing some jekyll theme. But now that I have a site, I’ll remain restless until I am actually satisfied with how it looks. So I have kind of cursed myself into learning web dev now. I look forward to finally understanding what all that css and html means inside those <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_layout/</code> folders.</p>

<p>As far as blog posts are concerned, I’ll start writing some math-y ones soon. I have like one or two planned and I’m honestly not able to do as much math as I’d like now so I don’t exactly have much interesting content at my disposal. But yeah parallely I’ll keep looking at how I can embed more complicated Latex in here, mainly say tikz figures. But from what ever research I have done today, I’ll probably have to settle with high quality images instead. We’ll see, I’ll find a way.</p>]]></content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Katex vs MathJax So today I tried to implement Katex. Its an alternative to MathJax with the advantage that it doesn’t take a stupidly long time to render and does not spill its gooey latex insides around while rendering. But Katex seems to have two problems Some of its font doesn’t match that of MathJax or Latex at all. Even in math mode all the characters feel like they have been written inside \text{}. It looks ugly and isn’t ideal but I was ready to reach a compromise somehow but that wouldn’t be possible because, Github, for some reason, doesn’t exactly like Katex. I dont understand the technicality of how or why, but it just feels too complicated to add Katex support right now. I mean it is very tempting but then it also isn’t an immediate necessity for the blog. It can wait. So in this round of Katex vs MathJax, MathJax wins. I’ll come around to this problem later in the future. What’s Next The terrible feeling that I’ll have to finally dip my toe into actual Web Dev, and understand properly what I’m doing, just keeps growing day by day. Customising the blog on my own will require proper css and html knowledge that I don’t posess right now. And while it’ll be intersting to learn, I don’t think I can learn at a pace where I can also implement what I’m learning at the same time. I say its a terrible feeling because its a far longer process than just installing some jekyll theme. But now that I have a site, I’ll remain restless until I am actually satisfied with how it looks. So I have kind of cursed myself into learning web dev now. I look forward to finally understanding what all that css and html means inside those _layout/ folders. As far as blog posts are concerned, I’ll start writing some math-y ones soon. I have like one or two planned and I’m honestly not able to do as much math as I’d like now so I don’t exactly have much interesting content at my disposal. But yeah parallely I’ll keep looking at how I can embed more complicated Latex in here, mainly say tikz figures. But from what ever research I have done today, I’ll probably have to settle with high quality images instead. We’ll see, I’ll find a way.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Making this blog - P1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/28/making-this-blog-p1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making this blog - P1" /><published>2023-06-28T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-06-28T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/28/making-this-blog-p1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/28/making-this-blog-p1.html"><![CDATA[<p>So I cant really figure out how to actually customise my existing theme or create a new theme for the website entirely. I had the idea that I would customise the blog a bit more before I started pushing in actual blog posts, but I figured I should start posting just for some dopamine hits and also so that I dont go crazy looking at the same few default blog posts everytime I loop this site up or do go to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">localhost:4000</code>.</p>

<p>I think this is a cool idea, posting here as I keep building this site. After all part of this site’s purpose is journaling and this is a good start. I’ll start removing the default posts as I fill the blog up with these. To keep these a little exciting until the “real” content starts coming, I’ll try to use some new markdown feature every post.</p>

<p>Okay so I enabled <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">detect Jekyll Front Matter</code> and another feature to render $\TeX$ let’s test it:</p>

\[y^3 = x^2 + Ax + B\]

<p>Yup it works. That’s a lot of new features for one post. I’ll push this to Github pages. It really takes very long for the deployment to actually update.</p>

<p>Here’s a random adjacency matrix just for fun.</p>

\[A=
\begin{bmatrix} 
0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 \\
1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 \\
0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 \\
1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 1 \\
0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 \\
0 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 \\
\end{bmatrix}\]

<p>Tomorrow I’ll see how I can fit more complicated latex and figures into this.</p>

<p>I almost tried to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">:wq</code> out of this.</p>]]></content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So I cant really figure out how to actually customise my existing theme or create a new theme for the website entirely. I had the idea that I would customise the blog a bit more before I started pushing in actual blog posts, but I figured I should start posting just for some dopamine hits and also so that I dont go crazy looking at the same few default blog posts everytime I loop this site up or do go to localhost:4000. I think this is a cool idea, posting here as I keep building this site. After all part of this site’s purpose is journaling and this is a good start. I’ll start removing the default posts as I fill the blog up with these. To keep these a little exciting until the “real” content starts coming, I’ll try to use some new markdown feature every post. Okay so I enabled detect Jekyll Front Matter and another feature to render $\TeX$ let’s test it: \[y^3 = x^2 + Ax + B\] Yup it works. That’s a lot of new features for one post. I’ll push this to Github pages. It really takes very long for the deployment to actually update. Here’s a random adjacency matrix just for fun. \[A= \begin{bmatrix} 0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 \\ 1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 \\ 0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 \\ 1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 1 \\ 0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 \\ 0 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 1 &amp;&amp; 0 &amp;&amp; 0 \\ \end{bmatrix}\] Tomorrow I’ll see how I can fit more complicated latex and figures into this. I almost tried to :wq out of this.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Test Post with MathJax</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/26/test-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test Post with MathJax" /><published>2023-06-26T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-06-26T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/26/test-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/26/test-post.html"><![CDATA[<p>test. hello.</p>

\[\int_{-\infty}^{\infty} e^{-x^{2}} dx = \sqrt{\pi}\]]]></content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[test. hello. \[\int_{-\infty}^{\infty} e^{-x^{2}} dx = \sqrt{\pi}\]]]></summary></entry></feed>